http://www.moonfruit.com/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
SiteMaker Software Limited ("SiteMaker", "we", "our" or "us") regards your privacy as very important.
We therefore follow strict security procedures in accordance with our legal obligations under the Data Protection Act 1998 (the "Act"). This policy sets out the basis on which we process any Personal Data we collect from you or that you provide to us when you use our website at www.moonfruit.com (the "Site"). It also tells you how we use cookies and other tracking technologies.
We will update this Privacy Policy from time to time so please check regularly to ensure that you are aware of the latest version.
What information do we collect and how do we use it?
1. Personal Data
In this Privacy Policy, "Personal Data" means any data relating to a living individual who can be identified from that data (or from that data and other information in our possession).
2. Email Address
2.1. When you first register on the Site as a user of SiteMaker, we ask for your email address.
We will use your email address to communicate important information about your account, such as payments due, or to reset your password.
2.2. If you have chosen to be on our mailing list, we send you our newsletter, and/or offers and promotions from SiteMaker about products or services that we consider to be relevant to you.
At the end of our newsletters or offers, we always provide you with the opportunity to remove yourself from our mailing list.
You may also opt in or out of either form of mailing by clicking My Details from the control bar of any site to which you are logged in, and select Edit my Details.
2.3. If you choose to become a member of one of our other customers' sites, you are agreeing to disclose your email address to the administrator of that site.
Through SiteMaker, a site administrator can choose to mail individual members, groups of members or the entire membership of the site.
When you join, you can choose to not be part of the mailing list. You can at any time choose to remove yourself from the mailing list of a site by using the unsubscribe function at the end of every email sent from the SiteMaker system.
2.4. If you are logged in to any SiteMaker site, and choose to post information, your posting will, by default, include your email address.
You can remove or edit this address before you submit your posting.
You may also choose to be notified by our system of replies or updates, in which case your email address will again be used.
2.5. If you build a site with us, you provide a site email address that is published on your site as a way of contacting the site owner.
This defaults to your private email address, but you can update the default email address to which it is routed through Manage Your Site.
3. Other Personal Data
3.1. If you choose to subscribe to SiteMaker, we ask you some additional personal questions such as your age, gender, occupation, postal/ZIP code and country. We also collect Personal Data about your browser, login times and IP addresses when you visit any SiteMaker sites.
3.2. We shall not disclose your Personal Data to any person except in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
4. Our Partners
4.1. If you have been introduced to SiteMaker by one of our partner organisations (a "Partner") which has provided your Personal Data to us in accordance with the terms and conditions of your agreement with that Partner and in accordance with that Partner's own privacy policy, we may disclose Personal Data back to that Partner in accordance with our contractual obligations to them.
4.2. Our Partners are required to comply with our Privacy Policy in relation to any Personal Data which we provide to them.
5. Our use of Personal Data
We use the Personal Data we collect from you to:
5.1. create your SiteMaker account;
5.2. deal with your inquiries and requests;
5.3. allow you to participate in any interactive features on the Site, where you choose to do so;
5.4. send you relevant communications, including announcements and administrative messages;
5.5. send you newsletters and information about products, services and promotions relating to us and/or our Partners or other organisations that we work with, in accordance with your communication preferences. You can control these updates by clicking My Details from the control bar of any site to which you are logged in, and selecting Edit my Details; and
5.6. understand how our customers use our services so that we can continuously improve the Site and the services we offer.
Personal Data may be used or shared with third parties if these third parties
are service providers and work on our behalf to support us in performing any of the
aforementioned purposes (e.g. marketing automation provider used by us to send you service or
marketing emails).
We may also generate, use and disclose aggregated and/or anonymised information
and statistics about the Site for marketing and strategic purposes. You will not be individually
identifiable from these aggregated and/or anonymised information and statistics.
6. Disclosure of Personal Data
6.1 Other than as expressly provided in this Privacy Policy, we may disclose your Personal Data:
6.1.1 to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the Companies Act 2006;
6.1.2 if SiteMaker Software Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by another company, in which case Personal Data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets; or
6.1.3 to the police or other regulatory authorities if we are legally required to do so as part of an investigation into illegal activities or as part of legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings.
6.2 If we are required to disclose Personal Data to any person outside the European Economic Area, we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your Personal Data is treated securely and in accordance with the Act.
7. Sensitive Personal Data
7.1. "Sensitive personal data" includes information about a person's racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or similar beliefs, trade union membership, physical or mental health or condition or sexual life, or about the commission of, or proceedings for, any offence committed or alleged to have been committed by that person, the disposal of such proceedings or the sentence of any court in such proceedings.
We do not intentionally collect or process any sensitive personal information about you and by law we may only process any such sensitive personal data under strict conditions.
7.2. You should only provide sensitive personal information to us if you are happy for us to have access to it. For the avoidance of doubt, if you give us, or give us access to, sensitive personal information, you are giving us your express consent to our processing it for the purposes of providing our services to you.
8. Principles of Data Protection
Our obligations under the Act are that all Personal Data must be:
8.1. processed fairly and lawfully;
8.2. processed for limited purposes and in an appropriate way;
8.3. adequate, relevant and not excessive for the purpose;
8.4. accurate;
8.5. not kept longer than necessary for the purpose;
8.6. processed in line with data subjects' rights;
8.7. secure; and
8.8. not transferred to people or organisations situated in countries without adequate protection.
9. Information Within Sites
9.1. You may include personal identifiable information in the site you create with SiteMaker.
If so, this is entirely at your own risk and we are in no way liable for the disclosure of this information.
We reserve the right to promote from time to time sites built with SiteMaker in accordance with our terms and conditions.
If so, we will make reasonable efforts to obtain the consent from the site administrator in advance.
9.2. Our site may include third party advertising and links to other websites and social networks.
Please note that we do not endorse or control the policies or practices of any website to which we provide a link or any social network to which you may have access through the Site.
You should always read carefully the privacy policy of any website you access or social network through which you share personal information in order to understand how they will use your data.
We do not disclose individually identifiable customer Personal Data to these advertisers or third party websites.
10. Credit/Debit Card Details, Billing Address and Payment History
10.1. We use a third party payment agent to manage our subscriptions via credit/debit card.
If you use this method of payment you will authorise regular payments to be made for your subscription to SiteMaker.
In doing so, you will be asked by the payment agent for your card details and billing address.
This information is held by the third party payment agent, and you will be asked to agree to their Privacy Policy in completing the payment steps.
10.2. We have no access to your credit/debit card details, but we may have access to your billing address and payment history in order to assist with customer service enquiries.
Under no circumstances are these details disclosed to any third parties.
11. Cookies
11.1. Cookies are small text files which are stored by the browser on your computer.
Only the information that you provide, or the choices you make while visiting a website, can be stored in a cookie. Allowing a website to create a cookie does not give that or any other site access to the rest of your computer, and only the site that created the cookie can read it.
11.2. We may use cookies to monitor how people use our site.
Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information, but they do allow us to remember your login details and therefore offer you a personalized service without you having to log in on every visit.
If you prefer not to use cookies, you can choose not to have your login details remembered on logging in or you can disable the feature in your browser.
11.3. Third party websites and advertisers may use technology to specific advertisements directly to your browser.
They automatically receive your IP address when this happens.
They may also use cookies and other technologies to personalise advertising content.
We do not have any control over such third party cookies or technologies and the information practices of those third parties are not covered by our Privacy Policy.
We exclude all liability for losses which you may incur when using third party websites.
12. How do we protect your personal information?
We want you to feel confident about using the Site and we are committed to protecting the personal information that we collect. We limit access to personal information about you to employees who reasonably need access to it to provide products or services to you, or in order to do their jobs. We have appropriate technical and organisational measures in place to protect the personal information you provide to us against unauthorised or unlawful use and against accidental loss, damage or destruction.
13. Your Consent
13.1. By registering with SiteMaker and using our services, you consent to the collection and use of information by us in the ways described above.
If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it. It is your responsibility to check regularly to see whether we have made any changes to our privacy.
13.2. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy or any changes we make to it from time to time, please do not continue to use the Site.
14. Contact us
You have the right to ask for a copy of any personal information that we hold about you in our records, to correct any inaccuracies in that information and to update any information that is out of date.
Please contact us via the link below should you wish to do so.
If you have any specific questions about this Privacy Policy or your relationship with us as a user of the Site, please contact us.
Back to the top
Company Info
Moonfruit is owned and operated by SiteMaker Software Ltd.
Address
SiteMaker Software Ltd
3 Waterhouse Square
138 Holborn
London
EC1N 2SW
United Kingdom
SiteMaker Software Limited is a UK company registered in England
Registered company number3871424
VAT registration numberGB 765346017
Need some help?
Responsive Pages
Account
SEO
Follow us:
Lots to see on the Blog
Signing up and transfe…
Signing up and transferring our domain name was quick and easy. Not only that but the support is great - questions answered quickly and in a friendly way. Overall, brilliant.
Jamie Rees
Moonfruit has enabled …
Moonfruit has enabled us and many other users of varying levels of experience to build great websites. We highly recommend it for small businesses and start-ups.
Steve Warren
If you want a self-bui…
If you want a self-build website but don't have the technical knowledge, then this is the site to use.
Bish
So easy to use to crea…
So easy to use to create your own website, but unlike other sites, you do not feel restricted to what you can achieve. You really can make your site look and operate exactly as you want it to!!
Andy
5
5
Fantastic service. So …
Fantastic service. So easy to work with and very on the ball when it comes to any (rarely occurring) issues. Nothing's impossible with this lot!
Claudia Kirkwood
5
5
We own a thriving smal…
We own a thriving small business, emphasis on small. We can't afford a development team or expensive website host, but 80% of our business comes from online search. We owe our business to Moonfruit.
Elaine Conces
4
5
Moonfruit has done me …
Moonfruit has done me proud. Feedback from potential customers has been that the website looks clean and professional.
Penny
5
5
Signing up and transfe…
Signing up and transferring our domain name was quick and easy. Not only that but the support is great - questions answered quickly and in a friendly way. Overall, brilliant.
Jamie Rees
5
5
Moonfruit has enabled …
Moonfruit has enabled us and many other users of varying levels of experience to build great websites. We highly recommend it for small businesses and start-ups.
Steve Warren
5
5
If you want a self-bui…
If you want a self-build website but don't have the technical knowledge, then this is the site to use.
Bish
5
5
So easy to use to crea…
So easy to use to create your own website, but unlike other sites, you do not feel restricted to what you can achieve. You really can make your site look and operate exactly as you want it to!!
Andy
5
5
Fantastic service. So …
Fantastic service. So easy to work with and very on the ball when it comes to any (rarely occurring) issues. Nothing's impossible with this lot!
Claudia Kirkwood
5
5
We own a thriving smal…
We own a thriving small business, emphasis on small. We can't afford a development team or expensive website host, but 80% of our business comes from online search. We owe our business to Moonfruit.
Elaine Conces
4
5
Moonfruit has done me …
Moonfruit has done me proud. Feedback from potential customers has been that the website looks clean and professional.
Forgotten your Password?
Please enter the email address you registered your account with. You need to follow the instructions provided in the email we send you.
Please enter a valid email address.
Submit
Close
Thank you!
An email explaining how to reset your password has been sent to following email:
Close
Close
Let’s sign you up, then...
Already have a Moonfruit account? Log in
or sign up using email
Password Strength
To create a strong password use a mixture of upper and lowercase characters,
numbers and non alphanumeric characters and make it at least 7 characters long.
Telephone number
Number may be used for SMS verification.
Remember me
sign me up
By signing up you agree to accept and adhere to our
terms and conditions and
privacy policy.
or
Hold on...
To get help you need to verify your email address. Check your inbox at:
Change
resend email
Oops...
Something's gone wrong and we can't log you into our support system
Contact us
Downgrade
You are no longer entitled to downgrade to this package because:
Until you correct this, you will renew on your exisiting package
We are using cookies to give you the best experience on our site. Cookies are files
stored in your browser and are used by most websites to help personalise your web experience.
By continuing to use our website, you are agreeing to our use of cookies. Please see our
Privacy Policy page for more details.
Continue
